Hello everyone, how are you all? I am your
personal advisor Amit Raj Sharma and you are
watching Yudh Real. In today's video,
we will understand the surrender value and reduced paid-up benefit of Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance Company
Limited's fixed life insurance plan
with an example. So, first of all, let's
talk
about the options of this plan. There are two options in this plan. The
first is the long term income
option and the second is the whole life income option. The
details of both are available in separate videos. If you
watch the video, you
will understand why they are different. The
thumbnails of both the videos are at the top of your screen.
You will find both these videos
in the life insurance playlist.
For your convenience, the link to the life insurance
playlist has already been given in the description of the video. So, let's
start today's video and learn the
details of the surrender value of Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance Company Limited's fixed life insurance plan. To enact the policy, you will have to pay
premiums continuously for at least 2 years.
Only after that will the policy
acquire the surrender value, that is,
before you can surrender the policy.  No, the
guaranteed surrender value in this
says that you will multiply the guaranteed surrender value factor by the
total premium
paid by you, the basic premium, then from that
you will subtract whatever
survival benefit you get, that is, income benefit and
its benefit is called guaranteed income in this plan. The
value that comes after subtracting it will be the
guaranteed surrender value.
In the case of both the options of this plan, that is,
long term income and whole life income, the
guaranteed surrender is calculated in a similar manner. Let
us take an example, let us take the man here.
Mr. is a doctor, so
I have written Mr. here. His
age is 40 years. He has opted for the
long term income option of the fixed life plan.
We are taking a premium payment of 10 years.
We will get a premium of 30 years.
With a premium payment term of 10 years, we are
paying a premium of ₹1 lakh annually
and have taken the benefit option number one which is
level income with lump sum benefit, that is,
income benefit as well as majority benefit.
So, in this case, the income benefit factor will be
37.5%, which will be applied to the annual premium.
Since the deferred period has
not been taken here, which is only one year in this plan, the
annual income
benefit will be 37.5% of Rs 1 lakh,
i.e. Rs 37,350, which he will continue to receive through the out positive
if he does not surrender the policy. So, what will be the
premium here in 10 years? If he is paying Rs 1
lakh every year, then the
premium payment term is 10 years, so he will pay a premium of Rs 10 lakh
here. Okay,
because we had to calculate the cylinder value,
we should know that
if
we do not take the deferred period, then the income
benefit period will also be of the same number of years as the policy term. Now, let us assume
that Mr. Di wants to surrender the policy after completion of 10 years of the policy. In
such a situation, we will see
how much total survival benefit he has received in the last 10 years.  If
we multiply 37350 by 10, the
amount will be 373500. In this case, the guaranteed
cylinder value factor will be 55%. So,
what does the guaranteed cylinder value mean?
Multiply the guaranteed surrender value factor by the
total weighted premium and
subtract the survival benefit received, that is,
subtract the guaranteed income benefit.
In this case, the guaranteed surrender
value that the policyholder will receive here will be
76500, right, and the policy will be
terminated here itself. Now, when it comes to the
loan,
you can take a minimum loan of ₹5000.
You can take a maximum loan of 80% of your surrender value. Along with
this, the rate of interest will be
8.1%, which keeps changing
with time; it is not fixed. Now, we need to
know from
where we got the guaranteed cylinder value factor. Now,
look at the table at the top of our screen. 30
years is positive. 10 years have been completed.  The
guaranteed cylinder value factor here is 55%.
Now you will get its complete PDF.
This video will be uploaded on the Telegram channel at 8:00 PM and by 9:00 PM
its PDF will also be shared on the Telegram channel
and for your convenience the
link of the Telegram channel has also been given
in the description of the video. Right now
we will talk about the 10 benefits here and the
majority benefit. In which case
is the reduction paid in the case of the policy, then we understand
what are the terms and benefit terms of the reduction policy here. The simple thing is that it is
mandatory to pay the premium for at least 2 years continuously. If after that you are
not able to pay the premium, then after the grace period the
policy will continue as an un-
reduced paid up policy and in such a case the
revival period will also be applicable which will be of five
years, that is,
even after the policy is converted into a reduction policy, you
can remove your policy again. So the
example that we have taken of Shriman Di here is
40 years, that is, we consider it here.  Age of 10 years premium
payment term right and 30 years positive
term running premium of ₹1 lakh, we are paying here so in
example if Mr.
Di paid premium for 5 years continuously and after that he is
not able to pay, then in such a case a reduction
factor will be calculated which says the
number of premiums, that is, the number of years he paid
premium, divide it by the
number of years he had to pay premium, so for
example if he paid premium for 10 years for 5
years, then we will divide the fifth
by 10, that is zero decimal fifth, here our
reduction factor will be calculated and it will be 10, so first of all let
us talk here,
in case of a policy, suppose
Mr. Di dies after completion of 20 years of the policy,
then we have to know here whether the
sum on death is right because the
benefit on death and death will be the death benefit,
what is the meaning of death and death, it is the reduction factor, in
case of a policy,
you will multiply the reduction factor, the
sum of the factor is
10 times the annual premium  That is, 10 lakh, if we multiply 10 lakh by 0.5 then the
reduced paid up sum of 5 lakh will be reduced here. Now
we
will compare the reduced paid up sum of 5 lakh, that is, the reduced paid up sum of 5 lakh. By subtracting 105% of the total paid premium,
what was the total paid premium?
₹5 lakh in 5 years. If we subtract 105% of ₹5 lakh, it
becomes 525000. Now if we compare these two, it is
more by ₹525000. If the
sum dies, then 525000 will be
given to the nominee of Shriman Di and the
policy will be closed here. Now
we will know about the maturity benefit here.
In the case of a reduced policy,
we know that Shriman Di paid the premium only for 5 years and did
not pay after that. It got
converted. We also know the reduction factor. So,
if he survives till maturity,
what will happen as soon as the policy is over?  This
is a Reduced Premium, the policy will be converted into a policy. All the income
benefits which are guaranteed incombnefit will stop
and the Guaranteed Income Benefit will be
converted into Terminal Value.
Okay, and the Maturity Benefit will
become Reduced Premium Maturity Benefit.
Now what is this Reduced Premium Maturity?
It is equal to Guaranteed Lumpsum
Benefit plus Terminal Value. Now this
Guaranteed Lumpsum Benefit is the same amount
which in normal conditions we call
Maturity Benefit, which is the guaranteed amount of the
terminal value of the total paid premium.
We will know this
in full detail now. Okay, but before that we will calculate the
Guaranteed Lumpsum Benefit Amount.
According to our example, the Maturity
Benefit Factor will be 55% and
in 10 years we would have paid Rs. 10 lakh as premium,
but here we have paid premium for only 5 years. The
policy is a Reduced Premium, in such a situation only 55% of Rs. 500000 will be calculated.  If it is
₹275000, then this will be
our guaranteed lumpsum benefit
amount here. Okay, now if I remind you here
that the example we have taken is of
long term income option, in
which we have taken benefit option number one
level income with lumpsum benefit option,
then our income benefit factor is
37.5%. Now we will calculate the remaining policy term here.
We will subtract the number of years we paid the premium from the policy term, it will be
25 years because we paid the
premium for only five years, so this
remaining policy term is minus the
remaining policy term which is 25 years. Here
you will also count the income benefit period,
although the income benefit will be lost,
but still we will need it for
calculation, hence I am telling you,
okay, your income benefit i.e.
survival benefit period is 25 years.
Now we have to know that 25 years is the total sum
of survival.  What would be the benefit? If
we take 37.5% of 1 lakh and multiply it by 25, then the
amount would be 933750. Okay, now
what does the terminal value say,
multiply the reduction factor by the total income
benefit which is the reduction paid, which has
started coming from the policy and is being received till maturity, that is, it is being
collected, right, then
how much is that total
933750. In this, if we multiply the release paid factor, then the
amount comes to 466875. So, in such a situation, on
maturity, Mr. Di will get the guaranteed
lumpsum benefit which is 275000 and the
terminal value which is
466875, then the total maturity benefit will be ₹ 10000
minus the reduced speed up
maturity benefit of
₹ 741875. So, if you have taken the long term income
option benefit and the policy is a
reduction paid policy, it gets converted into a reduction paid policy,
irrespective of the benefit option.  You will do the
calculation in this way. Okay, let me
remind you once again that if
you have turned off the long term income benefit
in this plan, then the benefits of the Reduce Paid Up
policy will be the same,
but you must have opted for the benefit option number 2,
where you used to
get the lump sum benefit on maturity, that will
not be available in the case of the Reduce Paid Up policy. And
if you have opted for the Whole Life Income option, then
also the calculation of the maturity benefit will be done in the same
manner as I
just told you, it will happen through an example.
Here, in the case of death benefit, if
you choose the Whole Life Income option, if the
policy gets converted into a Reduce Paid Up policy, watch the
video
on full screen to know what will happen. The death
benefit, the reduced Paid Up news on death, plus the
terminal value, plus the terminal value, plus the terminal value.
We will compare it with the surrender
benefit, i.e., the surrender value. And we
know that the cylinder value
always decreases with the total paid premium,
so the higher of these two will be the higher one for
comparison.  After that, the same will be your reduced policy
benefit in case of whole life income
and what will be the terminal value, the
reduction factor will be multiplied by the
total sum of income benefit which will be counted
when the policy is converted into a reduced policy from
there
till maturity, now see, you get special surrender value
when your policy
is converted into a reduced policy
but its method was not shown in the positive document,
so I could not tell you,
you watched the video till the end,
thank you very much for that, many thanks, now
you have to understand one thing yourself, you have
not explained it to others also that insurance is a protection
product, never take it incomplete and
definitely read the PDF from the Telegram channel, only then
you would be able to understand it well and
also be able to ask questions, thank you so much